Sergey Melnychuk

<u>linkedin.com/in/sergeymelnychuk</u> <u>github.com/sergey-melnychuk</u> <u>sergey-melnychuk.github.io</u>

Summary

Experienced and skilled software engineer, passionate about software architecture, domain-driven design, functional programming, large-scale distributed systems and machine learning, constantly pursuing self-improvement both personal and professional.

Skills

Large-Scale Distributed Systems, Data Structures and Algorithms Problem Solving, Design Thinking, TRIZ, DDD Java, Scala, Rust (C++, Go, Python, JavaScript) SQL / NoSQL, Cassandra, PostgreSQL, Spark, Kafka AWS, GCP, Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible, Jenkins Leadership, Agile, SCRUM, Lean, TDD, XP

Experience

09.2022 - Present: sergmeln.software (Self-Employed)

Building software solutions for complex sophisticated problems.

04.2022 - 09.2022: Meta (Facebook) (Software Engineer)

Service Health (C++, Python, JavaScript, React, Rust)

06.2021 - 03.2022: Starburst Data (Software Engineer)

Trino (https://github.com/trinodb/trino) (Java, Maven, GitHub)

11.2019 - 06.2021: Equinix (Staff Software Engineer)

Big Data Analytics, Internet of Things (Java, Scala, Akka, Kafka, Spark, AWS)

07.2018 - 10.2019: Google (Software Development Engineer)

Large-scale resource limits manager (C++), SaaS-enabling platform (Go, GCP)

07.2014 - 07.2018: StrikeAd (acq. by Sizmek) (Senior Scala Developer)

RTB DSP development: high-load, big-data (Erlang, Scala, Python, AWS)

Leading a cross-functional feature-team of up to 6 software engineers

06.2013 - 06.2014: EPAM Systems (Senior Java Developer)

09.2012 - 06.2013: EngagePoint (Java Developer)

02.2010 - 09.2012: Infopulse (Junior/Middle Java Developer)

Education

2006 - 2012: Master's Degree, Computer Science

NTUU "Kyiv Polytechnic Institute", IASA, System Design

Certifications

Apache Cassandra 3.x Developer Associate (Datastax, 2020)

Algorithms [by Robert Sedgewick] (2 parts, Princeton/Coursera, 2018)

Deep Learning Specialization [by Andrew Ng] (Coursera, 2018)

Functional Programming in Scala Specialization (EPFL/Coursera, 2018)

Oracle Certified Professional: Java SE 6 Programmer (Oracle, 2011)

Languages

English (fluent), Polish (fluent), Ukrainian (native), Spanish (beginner)